Karan Arora

Senior Software Developer

Contact

Address

Bangalore India

Phone

8968116247

E-mail

arora 15karan 1996@gmail.co m

Technical Profile

- Java
- Rest
- Spring Boot
- Maven
- MongoDB
- MySQL
- PostgreSQL
- Redis
- Git
- Amazon Web Services (AWS)

Competencies

Expert in Designing
Architecture (One-Pager/
LLD/ HLD) for scalable
Distributed systems.

Design Patterns

Architecture oversight

Experience in mentoring Junior Developers and conducting interviews.

Accomplished Senior Software Developer with 5 years of experience leading projects by acting as architect, developer and programmer analyst. Proficient in supporting project deliverables and maintaining releases. Strong leader in guiding support teams and solving complex issues. Steadfast in planning and implementing effective development strategies based on industry best practices.

Work History

2019-08 -Current

Senior Software Developer

Gainsight, Bangalore

Gong IO Integration:

- Integrated gong io platform with Gainsight, which brings calls/meeting data from gong to Gainsight in product area - timeline.
- Gong provides customer information around customer interactions, which is used to drive revenue intelligence
- Concepts: Background Processing, Indexing, Batching etc.

Customer Data Platform:

- Ingest data from multiple external systems and stitch data together into single system after applying different rules (algorithms) to identify duplicates.
- In short, it has 3 steps: connect, unify, and activate different jobs
- Performance evaluation 45 minutes for 1 Million records
- Concepts: Multi-threading, Indexing, Matching Algorithm, Fallback rules, Blocking Key, Batching,

Backaround Worker:

- Asynchronous application which picks job from database according to defined policy and executes it resiliently and takes care which job to run in parallel.
- Learnings: PostgreSql locks, parallel jobs, Jvisual VM, Multithreading.

2018-05 -2019-07

Software Developer

Evive HealthCare, Bangalore

Scheduler Service and File-Transfer:

 Scheduler service generates business reports at scheduled times using Spring

- Scheduler and transfers those to specified path after being generated by system.
- It reduces manual effort for file transfer to another machine

Migration - Monolithic to Microservices

- Transition from monolithic to microservices ecosystem
- Communication between microservices is achieved using service discovery tool consul
- Technologies: Java-8, Spring Cloud, Spring Boot, Consul

2017-05 -2018-04

Associate Software Developer

Evive HealthCare, Bangalore

- Developed Reports Feature using SQL for reporting services.
- Worked on Campaigns feature.
- Used analytical and problem-solving skills to understand/develop effective solutions for challenging situations.

Education

2018-12 - Certificate of Social Responsibility: Center Level Coordinator And Teacher

Bhumi - Bangalore

2014-05 - B.Tech: Computer Science

Chitkara University - Himachal Pardesh, India

• Received CGPA of 8.5